我想问你合并朱利亚诺需要什么，你是否认为这类似于......
I wanted to ask you what it took to incorporate Giuliano and if you think it's similar to what...
Te quería preguntar qué pesó para incorporar a Giuliano y si lo pensás parecido a lo que...
有时你会在年轻时使用球员。
Sometimes you use the player in youth.
A veces usas al jugador en la juventud.
Aniko González，使用整个侧面。
Aniko González, using the entire side.
Aniko González, utilizando todo el lateral.
谢谢。
Gracias.
嗯，下午好。
Well, good afternoon.
Bueno, buenas tardes.
嗯，是的，我们已经确认了纳韦尔和库蒂的伤亡情况。
Well, yes, we have confirmed the casualties of Nahuel and Cuti.
Bueno, sí, tenemos las bajas de Nahuel y de Cuti confirmadas.
嗯...
Um...
Ehm...
朱利亚诺的呼吁，嗯，原则上......
And Giuliano's call, well, in principle...
Y la llamada de Giuliano, bueno, en principio...
本来有可能直接给他打电话，结果他没有来。
There was the possibility that we would call him directly, in the end he didn't come.
Estaba la posibilidad de que lo llamemos directamente, al final no vino.
在第一次通话中，我谈论了这个约会，因为我已经参加过其他约会并且......
In the first call, I talk about this date because I have been on the others and...
En la primera llamada, hablo de esta fecha porque en las otras he estado y...
他是一个既可以踢右边也可以踢左边的球员
and he is a player who can play both on the right and on the left he can play
y es un jugador que puede jugar tanto por derecha por izquierda puede jugar
作为一名边锋，他可以踢边锋。
As a winger he can play as a winger.
De extremo puede jugar de carrilero.
考虑到我们面临的引用-取消引用的紧急情况，
and given the quote-unquote emergency we have,
y dada la entre comillas de emergencia que tenemos,
在边路，他是一位能为我们做出贡献的球员。
On the sides he is a player who can contribute to us.
En los laterales es un jugador que nos puede aportar.
如果有必要，如果你必须在右边或左边踢球，那么我们会寻找一个可以为我们解决这个问题的球员。
If necessary, if you have to play either on the right or on the left, then we look for a player who can solve the problem for us.
Llegado el caso si tiene que jugar tanto por derecha o por izquierda entonces buscamos un jugador que nos pueda solucionar
我们双方可能遇到的问题。
the problems we could have on the sides.
los problemas que podríamos tener en los laterales.
当我说横向时，不仅是防守，而且是边路，他是一名可以帮助我们的球员
and when I say lateral not only defensive but on the sides and he is a player who can help us
y cuando digo laterales no solo defensivo sino en la parte de los costados y él es un jugador que nos puede
他可以帮助我们，所以这就是他被召唤的原因。
He can help us, so that's what he was called for.
nos puede ayudar, así que para eso fue llamado.
你好，莱昂内尔，你好吗？
Hello Leonel, how are you doing?
Hola Leonel, ¿cómo te va?
嘿，想知道尼古拉斯怎么样，还有埃利亚菲科，他最后也……
Hey, wondering how Nicolás is, there's Eliafico who also ended up with...
Eh, preguntarte cómo está Nicolás, está Eliafico que terminó también con...
由于肩膀有问题，如果你认为他明天的比赛没问题，那么还有一点训练需要......
with shoulder problems, if you think he will be fine for tomorrow's game, there is still a little bit of training left to...
con problemas en el hombro, si crees que va a llegar bien para el partido de mañana, falta todavía un entrenamiento de un ratito para...
来定义它，但你认为你能够告诉它和另一个，如果你有点担心空中游戏的问题，他们已经变得相当
to define it but you think you will be able to tell it and the other if you are a little worried about the issue of the aerial game that they have become quite
para definirlo pero crees que lo vas a poder contar y la otra si te preocupa un poquito el tema del juego aéreo que les han convertido bastante
从这个意义上说，在过去的比赛中，他们显然在努力避免这种情况，对吧？
in that sense in the last games and it is something that they obviously work to avoid, right?
en ese sentido en los últimos partidos y es algo que obviamente trabajan para evitarlo, ¿no?
好吧，尼可，这些天我们尽力照顾他。
Well, Nicol, we try to take care of him these days.
Bueno, Nicol, lo intentamos cuidar estos días.
我没有和大部分人一起训练，只是为了照顾他们。
I have not trained with the bulk of the group, just to take care of them.
No he entrenado con el grueso del grupo, por cuidarlo solamente.
今天他将参加训练，我想他明天参加训练不会有任何问题。
Today he will be part of the training and I imagine he will have no problem being there tomorrow.
Hoy formará parte del entrenamiento y imagino que no tendrá problema para estar mañana.
至于死球，嗯，这是一个话题......
And as for the dead ball, well, it's a topic...
Y en cuanto a la pelota parada, bueno, es un tema...
每个人都有自己的意见，每个人都可以发表自己的意见
that everyone has their opinion and everyone can give their opinion
que cada uno tiene su parecer y cada uno puede opinar
我们场上的球员几乎都是这样的……
The players we have on the field are almost always of one...
Nosotros los jugadores que tenemos en la cancha son casi siempre de una...
嗯，我们的球队就是这样，我们防守得很好。
of a height, well, our team is what it is and we have defended well.
de una altura, bueno, nuestro equipo de lo que es y hemos defendido bien.
幸运的是，进球的时刻已经来临
and luckily well the goals have come the moments
y por suerte bueno han llegado los goles los momentos
准时、有逻辑地学习、工作，这就是你必须做的。
punctually and logically you study, you work and that is what you have to do.
puntuales y lógicamente se estudia, se trabaja y eso es lo que se tiene que hacer.
这就是我们将永远做的事情，但是嘿，我们的球员不会为此改变它。
and that is what we will always do, but hey, our players are not going to change it for that.
y es lo que haremos siempre, pero bueno, los jugadores nuestros no lo vamos a cambiar por eso.
Llorén，我们为 F3 和 ESPIEM 直播，一如既往的高兴。
Llorén, we are live for F3 and ESPIEM, a pleasure as always.
Llorén, estamos en vivo para F3 y ESPIEM, un placer como siempre.
我向你咨询了一个特殊的情况，歌海娜的情况，
I consult you about a particular situation, that of Garnacho,
Te consulto sobre una situación particular, la de Garnacho,
他还没有在阿根廷队参加过他的神圣比赛，
He has not had his consecrated match in the Argentine team,
no ha tenido su partido consagrativo en la selección argentina,
你必须要有耐心的信息是什么？
What is the message that you have to be patient?
¿Cuál es el mensaje que hay que tener paciencia?
还有其他人也像尼科·帕兹一样出道并表现得很好，但我也明白当时的背景……
There are other guys who have also debuted and have done very well like Nico Paz, but I also understand that the contexts...
Hay otros chicos que han debutado también y lo han hecho muy bien como Nico Paz, pero entiendo también que los contextos...
出道不同，需求也不同，但你的看法是什么呢？
debut have been different and the needs have been different, but what is your view?
de debut han sido diferentes y las necesidades han sido distintas, pero cuál es tu mirada
关于他们打过的这几场比赛以及关于他们的情况需要传达什么信息。
about these few games they have played and what is the message that needs to be conveyed regarding their situation.
sobre estos pocos partidos que han hecho y cuál es el mensaje que hay que bajar con respecto a su situación.
好吧，正如你所说，我认为比赛的时刻，对于尼科和......
Well, as you say, I think that the moments of the matches, both for Nico and...
Bueno, como bien vos decís, creo que los momentos de los partidos, tanto de Nico como de...
啤酒的味道根本不一样，一个人进入了一场与另一个人完全不同的游戏。
of Ale were not the same at all, one has entered a totally different game from the other.
de Ale no fueron iguales para nada, uno ha entrado en un partido totalmente diferente a otro.
我们也不能幸免，我们知道并理解其中的困难。
and we are not exempt from that, we know and understand the difficulty.
y nosotros no estamos exentos a eso, sabemos y entendemos la dificultad.
前几天的比赛，无论是对于艾尔还是对于必须进入的人来说，都没有空间，场地很拥挤
of the game the other day, both for Ale and for the one who had to enter, there was no space, the field was
del partido del otro día tanto para Ale como para el que le tocaba entrar, no había espacio, la cancha estaba
干燥，也许不是最喜欢的。
Dry and maybe not a favorite.
Seca y a lo mejor no favorita.
他的比赛，但我们需要让他上场，我们需要看到他参加这样的比赛。
to his game, but we needed to put him in, we needed to see him in a game like that.
a su juego, pero nosotros necesitábamos ponerlo, necesitábamos verlo en un partido así.
这样不仅是他，我们所有人和他的同伴都可以知道
and so that not only he but all of us and his companions can know
y para que no solo él sino todos nosotros y sus compañeros puedan saber
我们要找到什么。
what we are going to find.
lo que nos vamos a encontrar.
所以这个消息是安心的。
So the message is peace of mind.
Así que el mensaje es tranquilidad.
他们是年轻男孩，从逻辑上讲，我们非常信任他们，当时机成熟时，就轮到他们了
They are young guys who, logically, we trust them a lot and when the time comes, as it was their turn
son chicos jóvenes que lógicamente confiamos mucho en ellos y que cuando llega el momento como le tocó
第二天我们就把它给他戴上，我们不会有任何问题。
The next day we will put it on him, we will have no problems.
el otro día a él lo pondremos, no tendremos problemas.
超过，
Beyond,
Más allá,
它所面临的困难。
of the difficulty it has.
de la dificultad que tiene.
唯一能见到他们的方式，可惜我们没有友谊赛，我们没有机会说
The only way to see them, unfortunately we don't have a friendly match, we don't have the opportunity to say
La única manera de verlos, lamentablemente no tenemos partido amistoso, no tenemos la oportunidad de decir
我们可以在其他情况下尝试，就是这样，只要球队需要，就可以像往常一样将其延伸到球场上。
We can try in other contexts, it is what it is, stretching it onto the field whenever the team needs it, as always.
Podemos probar en otros contextos, es lo que hay, estirándolo a la cancha siempre que el equipo lo necesite, como siempre.
我们说。
we say.
decimos.
莱昂内尔，下午好。
Leonel, good afternoon.
Leonel, buenas tardes.
红色电台的古斯塔沃·亚罗克。
Gustavo Yarroch for Radio La Red.
Gustavo Yarroch para Radio La Red.
自从你公布名单以来...
Since you released the list...
Desde que diste a conocer la lista...
球队伤亡5人，你打电话给法昆多·梅迪纳和西蒙尼补偿一点。
The team suffered 5 casualties, you called Facundo Medina and Simeone to compensate a little.
La selección sufrió 5 bajas, llamaste a Facundo Medina y a Simeone para compensar un poco.
当你离开俱乐部时，你有遇到过任何负面反馈吗？
Did you encounter any negative feedback when you left a club?
Te encontraste con alguna negativa cuando se dieron las bajas de algún club?
然后我问你你想象明天对阵秘鲁的比赛是什么。
And then I ask you what game do you imagine tomorrow against Peru.
Y después te pregunto qué partido imaginás mañana contra Perú.
前几天我在记者会上回复过你，希望没有激怒你，我的回复很简短。
The other day I responded to you at the press conference, I hope I didn't anger you, I kept my response short.
El otro día te respondí en la rueda de prensa, espero que no te haya enojado, que la hice corta la respuesta.
但我回答了你的想法，但我觉得太简短了，仅此而已。
But I answered what you thought, but I think it was so brief, nothing more.
Pero te respondí lo que pensabas, pero yo creo que fue tan escueto, nada más.
不，但我留下来了。
No, but I stayed.
No, pero me quedé.
如果打扰到你了，请原谅我。
If it bothered you, forgive me.
Si te molestó, perdona.
没问题。
No problem.
No hay problema.
从现在起我忘记了这个问题。
From now on I forget the question.
De ahora me olvido la pregunta.
啊，消极的。
Ah, the negative ones.
Ah, de las negativas.
快点！
Come on!
¡Vamos!
不，是的，因为我前几天也有过这种情况，除了你之外，我从来没有遇到过问题，对任何人都很好，但对你就不那么有问题了。
No, yes, because I had it the other day and apart from you, I never had a problem, well with anyone, but less so with you.
No, sí, porque la tenía el otro día y aparte con vos, que nunca tuve problema, bueno con ninguno, pero menos con vos.
不，消极而不是没有，根本没有。
No, negative as opposed to none, not at all.
No, negativo al contrario de ninguno, para nada.
就朱利亚诺而言，情况更糟。
In the case of Giuliano, even less so.
En caso de Giuliano, menos todavía.
他的父亲会很高兴，我们也和古斯塔沃·洛佩斯谈过，他也
His father will be happy and we have also spoken with Gustavo López who also
su papá estará contento y hemos hablado también con Gustavo López que también
他是一名在这里度过了很多年的球员，知道对于一个男孩来说是什么样的。
He is a player who has spent a lot of years here and knows what it is like for a boy.
Es un jugador que ha pasado un montón de años acá y sabe lo que es para un chico.
正在玩这件衬衫并且......
was playing with this shirt and...
fue jugar con esta camiseta y...
这就是让我们最自豪的事情，孩子们愿意来。
That's what makes us most proud, that the kids want to come.
Eso es lo que más nos orgullece, que los chicos quieran venir.
他们不是第一次通话。
that they are not in a first call.
de que no estén en una primera convocatoria.
明天我们一如既往地期待一场比赛，似乎当有人回应时......
and tomorrow we expect a game as always, it seems that when one responds...
y mañana esperamos un partido como siempre, parece que uno cuando responde...
他放上磁带并播放，最后……
He puts on the cassette and puts play and at the end...
Se pone el cassette y pone play y al final...
观看比赛，看到比分，你就会意识到这场比赛有多么困难，最重要的是......
Watching the tie, seeing the scores, one begins to realize how difficult this tie is and above all that...
viendo la eliminatoria, viendo las puntuaciones uno se va dando cuenta de la dificultad que tiene esta eliminatoria y sobre todo que...
双方水平相当，在这种情况下秘鲁需要积分。
that the level is even and that in this case Peru is in need of points.
que el nivel es parejo y que en este caso Perú está necesitado de puntos.
他们需要补充，这使得游戏变得非常困难。
They need to add and that makes the game very difficult.
Necesita sumar y eso hace el partido muy difícil.
尽管前几天我们输了，但我们很认真并继续我们的路线。
We are serious and continue in our line even though we lost the other day.
Nosotros con seriedad y seguir en nuestra línea más allá de que el otro día hayamos perdido.
球队的路线是继续努力。
The team's line is to keep trying.
La línea del equipo es seguir intentándolo.
好吧，事情必须纠正，但有一些细微差别，但要努力。
And well, with the nuances that things have to be corrected, but trying.
Y bueno, con los matices de que se tienen que corregir cosas, pero intentándolo.
这里是 Leonel，Narela Centra，为 Dsports 直播。
Leonel here, Narela Centra, live for Dsports.
Leonel acá, Narela Centra, en vivo para Dsports.
根据您对朱利亚诺西蒙尼的回答，我问您是否在意他。
Based on what you answered about Giuliano Simone, I ask you if he is on your mind.
En base a lo que respondiste sobre Giuliano Simone, te consulto si está en tu mente.
以及是否有可能组成三名后卫线。
and if it is a possibility to form a line of three defenders.
y si es una posibilidad formar una línea de tres defensores.
其次，我想问你，你看重朱利安·阿尔瓦雷斯的什么特点、什么条件、什么，我想象与瓜迪奥拉看到的类似的东西。
And secondly, I want to ask you what characteristics, what conditions, what you value in Julián Álvarez, and I imagine something similar to what Guardiola saw.
Y en segundo lugar, te quiero consultar qué características, qué condiciones, qué valorás en Julián Álvarez, y me imagino que algo similar a lo que vieron Guardiola.
而此刻的西蒙尼，因为他们在整个进攻锋线的不同位置上都使用了他。
and Simeone at this moment, because they have used him throughout the attack front in different positions.
y Simeone en este momento, porque lo han utilizado en todo el frente del ataque en diferentes posiciones.
谢谢。
Gracias.
原则上是三人行，明天如果不出什么奇怪的事情我就看不到了。
In principle the line of three, for tomorrow if nothing strange happens I won't see it.
En principio la línea de tres, para mañana si no pasa nada raro no la veo.
我们相信三人线是一种选择，但我们必须努力，也许要按时完成。
We believe that the line of three is an option, but we have to work on it and maybe on time.
Creemos que la línea de tres es una opción, pero hay que trabajarla y a lo mejor puntualmente
在游戏的某个时刻，但不是一开始。
at one point in the game, but not at the beginning.
en un momento del partido, pero de inicio no.
朱利安，是的，他生来就是一名中场球员，他生来......
And Julián, well yes, he is born as a midfielder, he is born...
Y Julián, bueno sí, él nace media punta, nace...
在里面，让我们说，现在如果公平的话他拥有我们......
inside, let's say, and now if it's fair that he has us...
por adentro, digamos, y ahora si justancia da de que nos tenga...
不仅要把手放在一边
keep a hand on the side, not only
quedar una mano por un costado, no solo
因为我们认为这很有趣，但也因为……
because we think it can be interesting, but also because…
porque creemos que puede ser interesante, sino también ante…
不可能指望一些能够帮助我们的球员
the impossibility of being able to count on some players who can help us
la imposibilidad de poder contar con algunos jugadores que nos pueden
在两侧玩耍。
play on the sides.
jugar por los costados.
现在朱利亚诺来了，他可以给我们一些东西，我们也可以改变一些东西。
Now Juliano has come and can give us something and we can change something.
Ahora ha venido Juliano que nos puede aportar algo y podemos llegar a variar algo.
但原则上我们知道朱利安在他踢球的地方
but in principle we know that Julián where he plays
pero en principio sabemos que Julián donde juega
他嗅到了进球的味道，这很重要，他也为球队做了很好的工作，
he smells the goal and that is important and he also has a very good job for the team and
huele el gol y eso es importante y además tiene un trabajo para el equipo muy bueno y
对于任何教练来说这都很重要。
For any coach it is important.
para cualquier entrenador es importante.
教练，你好吗？
Coach, how are you?
Entrenador, ¿cómo estás?
Javier Aparicio，来自萨尔塔，第 10 队。
Javier Aparicio, from Salta, team 10.
Javier Aparicio, de Salta, equipo 10.
在过去的几天里，您谈到了这一需求，并将其预测到了明天的利害关系之外。
Last days you talked about the need, projecting this beyond what you have at stake tomorrow.
días pasados hablaste sobre la necesidad, proyectando este más allá de lo que tenés mañana en juego.
球员需要有上场时间。
the need for players to have minutes to play.
la necesidad que los jugadores tengan minutos de que jueguen.
你谈到了这一点，他们有必要参加比赛。
You talked about that, that it was necessary for them to play.
Hablaste de eso, que era necesario que jueguen.
您如何预测即将发生的事情？
How are you projecting what's coming?
¿Cómo vas proyectando lo que viene?
现在还剩一场比赛，明年还有六场比赛。
Now there is one game left, then there will be the six dates next year.
Ahora queda un partido, después van a quedar las seis fechas del próximo año.
它对结构有多重要？
How vital is it to the structure?
¿Qué tan vital es para la estructura?
的。
Of.
Ya.
他们踢球的技术方式，以及根据该计划，以及如何插入梅西。
in the technical way they play, and based on that plan, also how you insert Messi.
en lo técnico que jueguen, y en base a ese plan, también cómo insertás a Messi.
思考你的这一年、明年、即将发生的事情，因为很明显，无论谁踢球......
thinking about your year, next year, what's coming, because it's clear that whoever plays...
pensando su año, el próximo año, lo que viene, porque está visto que el que juega...
那些不参加比赛的人可能会面临不被征召的风险。
Those who do not play may run the risk of not being called up.
el que no juega, por ahí puede correr el peligro de no ser convocado.
我们需要球员上场比赛。
We need the players to play.
Necesitamos que jueguen los jugadores.
这六场比赛的比分非常接近。
These six games were very close.
Estos seis partidos fueron muy seguidos.
美洲杯结束后，一切都非常接近，所以我们非常选择，我前几天说过，继续我们的基础......
After the Copa América, everything was very close, so we very much chose, I said it the other day, to continue with the basis that we...
después de la Copa América, fue todo muy seguido, entonces optamos mucho, lo dije el otro día, de seguir con la base de que nos...
我们没有得到奖杯的乐趣，也没有太多的时间
that we didn't get the joy of the Cup and that there wasn't as much time to
que nosotros no nos dio la alegría de la Copa y que no hubo tanto tiempo de
带上其他球员，但确实从现在开始我们需要每个人都参加比赛
to bring other players, but it is true that from now on we need everyone to play
de traer a otros jugadores, pero sí es verdad que a partir de ahora necesitamos que todos jueguen
然后从那里决定每个人的足球水平，就像我们一直做的那样。
and from there decide on the football level of each one, as we have always done.
y a partir de ahí decidir por el nivel futbolístico de cada uno, como siempre hemos hecho.
除了这一次，正如我前几天所说的，我们在某些情况下选择......
except this time, which as I said the other day, we opt in some cases...
salvo esta ocasión, que como dije el otro día, optamos en unos casos...
因为我们认为他们是重要的参与者，我们必须给予他们权利。
because we consider that they are important players and we would have to give them the right.
porque consideramos que son jugadores importantes y le tendríamos que dar la derecha.
狮子座的情况同样如此，但情况却截然不同。
In the case of Leo the same, it is a quite different case.
En el caso de Leo lo mismo, es un caso bastante diferente.
他总是在比赛，相反，有时即使他必须休息也会更好。
He always plays and on the contrary, sometimes even if he had to rest it would be better.
El juega siempre y al contrario, a veces hasta que tendría que descansar sería mejor.
除了...之外我们没有想太多
We don't think much beyond...
No pensamos mucho más allá de...
但确实，球员们很重要
but it is true that it is important that the players
pero sí es verdad que es importante que los jugadores
我有这些连续性的人。
I have these guys in continuity.
Tengo en continuidad estos chicos.
不管他们玩得多少，他们每个月都会玩两到三场比赛。
No matter how little they play, they play two or three games a month.
Por poco que jueguen, al mes juegan dos o tres partidos.
这就足够了。
and that would be enough.
y con eso bastaría.
另一件事是他们几乎不玩任何东西。
Another thing is that they don't play practically anything.
Otra cosa es que no jueguen prácticamente nada.
Leo，acá，来自福克斯体育的尼古拉斯·诺伊斯。
Leo, acá, Nicolás Neus from Fox Sports.
Leo, acá, Nicolás Neus de Fox Sports.
您已经知道决赛何时举行吗？
Do you already have information on when the final will be played?
¿Ya tenés información de cuándo se va a jugar la finalísima?
另一个问题与明年有关。
And another question related to next year.
Y otra pregunta relacionada al año que viene.
您是否考虑过组建一支当地足球队的可能性？
Do you contemplate the possibility of putting together a local soccer team?
¿Contemplás la posibilidad de armar una selección del fútbol local?
谢谢。
Gracias.
原则上我没有关于该游戏的任何消息。
In principle I don't have any news about that game.
En principio no tengo ninguna noticia del partido ese.
据我所知，我想我上次已经说过了
For all I know, I think I said it last time,
Por lo que sé, creo que lo dije la otra vez,
明年并不容易，因为西班牙队有比赛
It is not easy for next year because Spain plays
no está fácil para el año que viene porque España juega
世界杯预选赛虽然复杂，但也不错。
World Cup qualification and it is complicated, but good.
clasificación del Mundial y está complicado, pero bueno.
我不知道他们是否会寻找所有日历的日期，这很奇怪，我没有看到它，但是嘿，我们会看到的。
I don't know if they will look for a date with all the calendar, which is strange, I don't see it, but hey, we'll see.
No sé si buscaran una fecha con todo el calendario que es raro que hay, no la veo, pero bueno, ya veremos.
另一个稍后，好吧，另一个问是否...
and the other one later, well, the other one asks if...
y la otra después, bueno, la otra pregunta si...
这已经被谈论了很多年，但今天却非常困难。
This has been talked about for years, but today it is very difficult.
Hace años que se está hablando de esto, pero hoy en día es muy difícil.
使用U-20进行训练非常困难。
It is very difficult to train with the U-20.
Es muy difícil entrenar con la Sub-20.
实际上是把球员带到这里训练，因为他们是甲级联赛，这非常复杂。
practically bringing the players to train here because they are in the first division and it is very complicated.
prácticamente traer a los jugadores a entrenar acá porque están en primera división y es muy complicado.
所以我什至不告诉你组建一支当地足球队。
so I don't even tell you to make a local soccer team.
así que ni te digo a hacer una selección del fútbol local.
这对双方来说都是可以理解的，对俱乐部来说也是如此。
It is understandable on both sides, on the side of the clubs as well.
Es entendible de los dos lados, del lado de los clubes también.
事实上，当前的日历很复杂。
The truth is that with the current calendar it is complicated.
La verdad es que con el calendario de ahora es complicado.
拉斐拉观察家广播电台的莱昂内尔·内斯托·克利瓦蒂。
Leonel Néstor Clivaty from Radio El Espectador de Rafaela.
Leonel Néstor Clivaty de Radio El Espectador de Rafaela.
明天的比赛将是球队9个月内踢的16场比赛。
With tomorrow's game there will be 16 games that the team played in 9 months.
Con el de mañana van a ser 16 partidos que jugó el equipo en 9 meses.
如果我们加上奥塔门迪和朱利安，如果我们考虑的话，就是20……
and if we add Otamendi and Julián, 20 if we consider...
y si agregamos a Otamendi y a Julián, 20 si consideramos...
奥运会的那些。
those of the Olympic Games.
los de los Juegos Olímpicos.
您通常会注意到任何饱和症状吗？
Do you generally notice any symptoms of saturation?
¿Notas en general algún síntoma de saturación?
团队如何应对这样的压力，我认为这是历史性的，这一年......
How the team copes with such stress, I think it is historic, a year with...
cómo sobrelleva el plantel semejante estrés, creo que es histórico, un año con...
16 到 20 场比赛以及所有......
between 16 and 20 games and all...
entre 16 y 20 partidos y todos...
有很大的要求或应对它们
of great demands or copes with them
de grandes exigencias o los sobrelleva
正是凭借这种慷慨和动机，例如，这些动机使他在最近赢得了一切。
with that generosity and with those motivations that, for example, have led him to win everything in recent times.
con esa generosidad y con esas motivaciones que, por ejemplo, lo han llevado a ganar todo en los últimos tiempos.
谢谢。
Gracias.
这是一个好问题，因为我没有添加游戏，但这是一个好问题。
It's a good question because I hadn't added up the games, but it's a good question.
Es una buena pregunta porque no había sumado los partidos, pero es una buena pregunta.
特别是因为我们到达这个阶段，明天的比赛，感觉
Especially because we arrive at this stage, tomorrow's game, with the feeling
Sobre todo porque llegamos a esta instancia, al partido de mañana, con la sensación
我不知道这是不是饱和，但就是我们在一起很多次的感觉。
I don't know if it's saturation, but it is with the feeling that we have been together a lot.
No sé si saturación, pero sí con la sensación de que hemos estado muchísimo juntos.
非常非常。
Very, very much.
Muchísimo, muchísimo.
之前的感觉是我们很少见到他。
and when before the feeling was that we saw little of him.
y cuando antes la sensación era que lo veíamos poco.
当然，如果你添加他们俱乐部没有休息的比赛......
Then of course, if you add to them the matches of their clubs that have not had a rest...
Entonces claro, si a ellos les suma los partidos de sus clubes que no han tenido descanso...
我为我自己负责，因为我是一名教练，但对他们来说……
I am answering for me because I am a coach, but to them...
Yo estoy respondiendo por mi que soy un entrenador, pero a ellos...
因此，这肯定是有关日历的一个经常被谈论的话题。
So it is surely a topic that is being talked about a lot about the calendar.
Así que seguramente es un tema que se está hablando mucho del tema del calendario.
但在选拔层面...
But at the selection level...
Pero a nivel de selección...
所以感觉特别是从六月份开始，从六月份到现在我们玩了很多，我们...
So the feelings especially from June, from June until now we have played a lot, we have...
Así que las sensaciones sobre todo a partir de junio, de junio hasta acá hemos jugado un montón, hemos...
但对它的反应是美妙的，超越......
but the response to it is wonderful, beyond...
pero la respuesta de ello es maravillosa, más allá de...
结果，无论打得好还是坏，精彩，他们都在这里，他们都很高兴。
results, playing well or badly, wonderful, they are here, they are happy.
resultados, jugar bien o mal, maravillosas, están acá, están felices.
这是发生在我们身上最好的事情，但事实是……
And that is the best thing that is happening to us, but it is true that...
Y eso es lo mejor que nos está pasando, pero sí es verdad que...
很多游戏都缺少这种感觉。
The sensations are missed in many games.
las sensaciones se extrañan en muchos partidos.
莱昂内尔在这里，这里。
Here Leonel, here.
Acá Leonel, aquí.
太感谢了。
Thank you so much.
Muchas gracias.
来自 Channel 12 和 FM del Viento de Chubut 的 Augusto Arraquijar。
Augusto Arraquijar from Channel 12 and FM del Viento de Chubut.
Augusto Arraquijar de Canal 12 y FM del Viento de Chubut.
你刚刚指出了一些你对与秘鲁队的比赛的期望，并且你已经指出这将是
You just pointed out a little about the game you expect with Peru and you had marked that it was going to be
señalaste recién un poco del partido que esperás con Perú y habías marcado que iba a ser
和巴拉圭的比赛很不一样，最后一天的一些表现
very different from the Paraguay match, some of the performance of the last day
muy diferente al partido de Paraguay algo del rendimiento de la última jornada
声音和教练组的变化为明天的比赛做准备
changes in voice and in the coaching staff to prepare for tomorrow's game
cambia en voz y en el cuerpo técnico para preparar el partido de mañana
不久之后，你在过去几个小时的一些报告中谈到了波切蒂诺。
and a short time later you talked about Pochettino in the last few hours, in some report you gave.
y una cortita después hablaste de Pochettino en las últimas horas, en algún reportaje que diste.
在最后几个小时里他对你称赞了很多，不仅是你和你的教练组，而且他有话要说
and in the last hours he praised you a lot, not only you and your coaching staff, but he had words
y él en las últimas horas te elogió mucho, no solamente a vos y tu cuerpo técnico, sino que tuvo palabras
作为总监、团队负责人，我非常赞赏你。
very complimentary, speaking from you as director, as head of the team.
muy elogiosas, hablando vos como director, como cabeza de equipo.
并思考作为一支你认为如此与众不同的球队的教练所面临的困难。
and thinking about the difficult place of being a coach of a team that you had marked as being so different.
y pensando en el lugar difícil de ser entrenador de una selección que vos habías marcado tan distinto a ser.
一支球队的教练。
coach of a team.
entrenador de un equipo.
太感谢了
Thank you so much
Muchas gracias
我没有听波切的话，但他站在我的人民一边。
I didn't listen to Poche, but he was on the side of my people.
No lo escuché a Poche, pero él era al lado de mi pueblo.
这是来自 Murfi 的，我是投标人，所以...
It's from Murfi and I'm a bidder, so...
Es de Murfi y yo soy pujato, así que...
我不可能说坏话。
It's impossible for me to say something bad.
imposible que diga algo malo.
我给你一个拥抱。
I send you a hug.
Le mando un abrazo.
嗯，至于前几天的比赛和今天的比赛对比，你看。
Well, as for the game the other day compared to this one, look.
Bueno, en cuanto al partido del otro día comparado con el de este, mirá.
前几天我有自己的观看比赛的方式，但事实并非如此
I have my way of watching the game the other day, beyond the fact that
Yo tengo mi manera de ver el partido del otro día, más allá de que
我相信巴拉圭的优点是存在的，我认为应该给予它，因为最终我们总是与对手比赛。
I believe that Paraguay's merit is there and I think it should be given because in the end we always play against a rival.
Yo creo que el mérito de Paraguay está ahí y me parece que hay que ponerlo porque al final jugamos contra un rival siempre.
但球队总是试图表现出尝试过的感觉
but the feeling the team always tried to play tried
pero la sensación el equipo intentó siempre jugar intentó
停留情境，承担风险，一起度过。
Stay situations, took risks, together pass.
Queder situaciones, se arriesgó, junto pase.
这就是你事后留下的感觉吗？
And that's the feeling you're left with afterwards?
¿Y eso es la sensación que uno se queda después?
总是有改进的空间，但团队有这种感觉，我们将继续沿着这些路线前进。
There is always room for improvement, but the team has that feeling and we are going to continue along those lines.
Se puede mejorar siempre, pero esa sensación el equipo la tiene y nosotros vamos a seguir en esa línea.
我们要改变它。
we are going to change it.
nos la vamos a cambiar.
最重要的是，因为对手并不完全相同，他们的比赛方式不同，他们没有相同的体系。
and above all because the rivals are not all the same, they do not play in the same way, they do not have the same system.
y sobre todo porque los rivales no son todos iguales, no juegan de la misma manera, no tienen el mismo sistema.
所以他们将对这两款游戏进行一些描述。
so they are going to be a bit of a description of these two games.
así que van a ser un poco la descripción de estos dos partidos.
我们将找到一个不同的对手，最重要的是我们在主场与球迷一起比赛，这将是很重要的。
We are going to find a different opponent and above all that we are playing at home and with our fans it is going to be important.
Vamos a encontrarnos un rival diferente y sobre todo que jugamos de local y con nuestro público va a ser importante.
莱昂内尔，这里是为 Clarín 报纸报道的一个好小故事。
Leonel, here, a good little story for the Clarín newspaper.
Leonel, acá, una buena ancillota para el diario Clarín.
有几次你不得不发现自己陷入了这个循环。
A couple of times you had to find yourself in this cycle.
Un par de veces te tuviste que encontrar en este ciclo.
败局如此，幸好人数不多，但有什么？
With this circumstance of defeat, luckily there were not many but what has
con esta circunstancia de derrota por suerte no fueron muchas pero lo que tiene
你们的球队有很多优点，每次我输球，他们都会很快恢复过来，我立即做出反应，他们在世界杯上晋级了。
Among so many good things about your team, every time I had a defeat they quickly recovered, I had an immediate reaction, they passed it in the World Cup.
entre tantas cosas de bueno tu equipo es que rápidamente cada vez que tuve una derrota se repuso tuve una reacción inmediata la pasó en el mundial
西内马莱霍队对阵乌拉圭队，最终马拉卡尼队获胜。
Cinemalejo happened against Uruguay, which was the Maracaní that won.
Cinemalejo le pasó contra Uruguay que fue el Maracaní que ganó.
考虑到以前的经历，您怎么看？
Taking into account those previous experiences, how do you see?
teniendo en cuenta esas experiencias anteriores, ¿cómo ves?
前几天失败后的脸，如果你看到它相同，如果你看到它不同。
the face after this defeat the other day, if you see it the same, if you see it different.
el semblante después de esta derrota el otro día, si lo ves igual, si lo ves distinto.
我宁愿不失去，重新获得尊重......
I prefer not to lose, to regain esteem...
prefiero no perder, para recuperar la estima...
总是更好地获胜或总是更好的积极结果，但如果这是真的
always better to win or always better positive results but if it is true that
siempre mejor ganar o siempre resultados positivos mejor pero si es verdad que
失去是有方法和手段的。
There are ways and means to lose.
hay maneras y maneras de perder.
大多数时候...
Most of the time...
La mayoría de las veces...
我们已经失去了这些，但事实上它们是重要的打击，尤其是阿拉伯半岛。
that we have lost, beyond the fact that they were important blows, especially Arabia.
que hemos perdido, más allá de que fueron masazos importantes, sobre todo la Arabia.
在我们没有预料到的情况下。
in conditions that we did not expect.
en condiciones que no la esperábamos.
大多数时候球队给人一种很好的感觉，然后我总是说
Most of the time the team had given a good feeling and then I always say
La mayoría de las veces el equipo había dado buenas sensaciones y entonces siempre digo
知道对手更优秀而输掉比赛，与知道今天你做了必须做的事情而输掉比赛是不同的。
Losing knowing that your opponent was superior is not the same as losing knowing that today you did what you had to do.
No es lo mismo perder sabiendo que el rival fue superior, a perder sabiendo que hoy hiciste lo que tenías que hacer.
你必须纠正一些事情，但你做了你必须做的事情，最终这就是足球，这就是我们有时总是说的……
You have to correct things but you did what you had to do and in the end it's football, that's what we always say that sometimes...
Tienes que corregir cosas pero que hiciste lo que tenías que hacer y al final es fútbol, es lo que siempre decimos que a veces...
在足球比赛中，如果总是由踢得最好的球员获胜，那会很无聊，所以才会有这些东西。
In football, if the player who plays the best always wins, it would be very boring, that's why it has these things.
En el fútbol si ganaría siempre el que juega mejor sería muy aburrido, por eso tiene estas cosas.
但如果它确实稍微强化了这个信息，而这就是他们所知道的，那么这个信息就是团队
but if it is true that it reinforces the message a little and that is what they know, the message is that the team
pero si es verdad que refuerza un poco el mensaje y eso es lo que ellos saben el mensaje es que el equipo
它必须继续这条线，以及我们已经告诉过你的细微差别，我们必须尽量不重复它。
It has to continue with this line, with the nuances that we already told you and we have to try not to repeat it.
Tiene que seguir con esta línea, con los matices que ya les dijimos y tenemos que intentar que no se repita.
莱昂内尔，这里是奥克塔维奥·彼得里克，与维克多·雨果的关系。
Leonel, here Octavio Petric, for Relatories with Víctor Hugo.
Leonel, acá Octavio Petric, para Relatories con Víctor Hugo.
你好吗？
How are you?
¿Cómo estás?
我想向您咨询一下贡萨洛·蒙迪尔（Gonzalo Mondiel）的具体案例。
I want to consult you about the specific case of Gonzalo Mondiel.
Te quiero consultar por el caso específico de Gonzalo Mondiel.
显然，每次他来，他都有表现，他达到标准，他在国家队被奉献，他赢得了一切
Obviously every time he came, he performed, he measured up, he was consecrated in the national team, he won everything
Obviamente cada vez que vino, rindió, dio la talla, consagrado en la selección, ganó todo
当他们使用它时，它是在水平上的，但在他们的俱乐部中，它与当前事件形成对比。
and when they use it it is at the level, but in their club it contrasts with current events.
y cuando lo utilizan está a nivel, pero en su club contrasta la actualidad.
只需几分钟。
just a handful of minutes.
apenas un puñado de minutos.
作为一名球员，你当时也会担心这些事情
You as a player also at the time those things worry you
Vos como jugador también en su momento esas cosas los inquietan
您谈论连续性已经有一段时间了。
You have been talking about continuity for some time now.
Venís hablando hace un tiempo ya de la continuidad.
你能告诉我关于他的什么吗？
What can you tell me about him?
¿Qué me podés decir de él?
我们想象他明天开始。
We imagine him starting tomorrow.
Lo imaginamos titular mañana.
谢谢。
Gracias.
是的，嗯，这是我之前被问到会议记录问题的案例之一，如果它很重要的话。
Yes, well, it is one of the cases that I was asked before about the issue of minutes, if it is important.
Sí, bueno, es uno de los casos que antes me preguntaban del tema de los minutos, de si es importante.
在这一天，在这六个人聚集在一起的日子里，我们选择他们继续和我们在一起。
On this date, on these six that came together, we opt for them to continue being with us.
En esta fecha, en estas seis que vinieron juntos, optamos a que ellos sigan estando con nosotros.
并给予他们权利，因为我们相信他们应得的，因为我们也相信寻找替代者
and give them the right because we believe they deserve it and because we also believe that looking for replacements
y darle la derecha porque creemos que la merecen y porque creemos también que buscar reemplazantes
我们不清楚，这也没有多大意义。
that we weren't clear on, it didn't make much sense either.
que no teníamos claro, tampoco tenía mucho sentido.
就贡萨洛而言，他是一个男孩，当你看到他训练时，当你看到他比赛时，
and in the particular case of Gonzalo, he is a boy who, when you see him train, when you see him compete,
y en caso particular de Gonzalo es un chico que cuando lo ves entrenar, cuando lo ves competir,
很难将其排除在外，它们是非常特殊的情况
It is very difficult to leave it out, they are very particular cases
es muy difícil dejarlo afuera, son casos muy particulares
他在团体中很受欢迎，而且
He is very loved within the group and also
es muy querido dentro del grupo y además
他想把它带回家，因为你的训练方式令人难以置信。
He wants to take it home because the way you train is something incredible.
te lo quiere llevar a tu casa porque como entrenas es algo increíble.
并非所有案件都是相同的，所以贡萨洛的案件不止于此……
Not all cases are the same, so Gonzalo's case beyond that...
no todos los casos son iguales, entonces el caso de Gonzalo más allá de que...
我们希望并且需要他打球，打更多比赛
We would like and need him to play, to play more
Quisiéramos y necesitaríamos que juegue, que juegue más
他是一个特例，因为我们非常欣赏他，每次他上场，他都会为我们做出贡献。
He is a special case because we appreciate him a lot and every time he has been on the field he has contributed to us.
Es un caso especial porque lo apreciamos un montón y cada vez que ha estado dentro de la cancha nos lo ha aportado.
这就是为什么案例并不完全相同，我们希望它能够
That is why the cases are not all the same and we hope that it can
por eso que los casos no son todos iguales y esperemos que pueda
享受他想要的、我们也需要的那些分钟。
enjoy those minutes that he wants and that we also need.
gozar esos minutos que él quiere y que nosotros también necesitamos.
莱昂内尔，你好吗？
Leonel, how are you doing?
Leonel, ¿cómo te va?
Nicolás Maipara、Cadena 3、Santa Fe 和 Central Deportiva。
Nicolás Maipara, Cadena 3, Santa Fe and the Central Deportiva.
Nicolás Maipara, Cadena 3, Santa Fe y la Central Deportiva.
两个问题。
Two questions.
Dos preguntas.
根据他的分析，梅西的这一年是从他的伤病开始的。
Messi's year, the analysis he makes, began with the injury there.
El año de Messi, el análisis que hace, se empezó con la lesión allá.
在萨尔瓦多与国际迈阿密的人们一起，然后他们也在亚洲。
in El Salvador with the people from Inter Miami, then they were also in Asia.
en El Salvador con la gente de Inter Miami, luego estuvieron también en Asia.
正如你所看到的，美洲杯和这一系列比赛中发生了什么。
what happened in the Copa América and this whole series of matches, as you have seen.
lo que sucedió en la Copa América y toda esta seguidilla de partidos, como lo has visto vos.
另一个则必须看看这是否让他们担心、让他们担心还是什么都不担心。
and the other has to see if it worries them, worries them or nothing.
y la otra tiene que ver si les inquieta, les preocupa o nada.
事实上，如果阿根廷明天不能获胜，它将失去国际足联排名的领先地位。
the fact that if Argentina does not win tomorrow it would lose the leadership of the FIFA ranking.
el hecho de que si Argentina no gana mañana perdería el liderazgo del ranking FIFA.
狮子座的年份是具有以下特征的玩家的年份
The year of Leo is the year of a player who has
El año de Leo es el año de un jugador que ha
他打了很多比赛，他在很多比赛中都有上场。
He's played a lot of games he's been available in a lot of games.
Ha jugado un montón de partidos que ha estado disponible en un montón de partidos.
中间有美洲杯。
that has had a Copa América in the middle.
que ha tenido una Copa América en el medio.
而如今，这对...来说是非常困难的。
and nowadays it is very difficult for...
y que hoy en día es muy difícil que...
玩家或该类型的玩家处于 100% 状态并且没有出现任何问题。
players or that that type of player is at 100% and has not had any problems.
jugadores o que ese tipo de jugadores esté al 100% y que no haya tenido algún problema.
我认为这是正常的一年
I see it as a normal year in terms of
lo veo un año normal en cuanto a
就比赛而言，他确实受过伤，而且
to games, it is true that he has suffered that injury and
a partidos, es verdad que ha sufrido esa lesión y
他的计划对我们有一点影响，但总的来说，他对我们一直很好。
and that his plans affected us a little, but in general he has always been good with us.
y que nos tocó un poco sus planes, pero en general con nosotros siempre ha estado bien.
它是现场直播的。
and it was live.
y que era en vivo.
不，事实是这并不让我担心，我也不担心......
No, the truth is that it doesn't worry me, nor do I worry that...
No, la verdad que no me preocupa, como tampoco me preocupa que...
那...也就是说，如果我们仍然是第一或者是第一，那么，我不...
that... that is, if we are still first or were first, well, I don't...
que... o sea, si somos primero todavía o éramos primeros, bueno, no me...
统计数据就在那里，但我不认为...
The statistics are there and I don't think it's...
Está ahí la estadística y no creo que sea...
重要的是明天赢球，其他的都是次要的。
The important thing is to win tomorrow and then the other thing is secondary.
Lo importante es ganar mañana y después lo otro ya es secundario.
他就是他，来自 Ciudadanado 电台 Vitalum 的 Maxi。
There he is, Maxi from Vitalum for Radio Ciudadanado.
Ahí está, Maxi de Vitalum para Radio Ciudadanado.
他们只是在谈论失败的话题吧？
They were just talking about the topic of defeats, right?
Hablaban recién del tema de las derrotas, ¿no?
球队已经习惯了胜利，但失败......
and the team is used to winning so much, but the defeats...
y está acostumbrado a ganar el equipo tanto, pero las derrotas...
他们是否让你担心，或者他们是否邀请你反思并尝试用新的东西重塑自己？
Do they worry you or do they invite you to reflect to try to reinvent yourself with something new?
¿Te preocupan o invita a la reflexión para tratar de reinventarse con algo nuevo?
现在我回到古斯塔沃问我的问题是否让我担心。
Now I return to what Gustavo asked me if it worries me.
Ahora vuelvo a lo que me preguntó Gustavo si me preocupa.
我担心我们是否有不想失去的感觉。
I worry if the sense of we don't like to lose.
me preocupa si el sentido de no nos gusta perder.
但当你加入的时候你就失去了...
but when you join the way you lose...
pero cuando se une a la manera que pierda...
你不再担心，没有人喜欢失败，这是显而易见的
You stop worrying less, nobody likes to lose, it's obvious
te deja de preocupar menos, a nadie le gusta perder, es evidente
不知道多久前就说过了，我们要知道，最后可能会失去。
I don't know how long ago I said it, we have to know that it can be lost in the end.
No sé cuánto hace que lo dije, tenemos que saber que se puede perder al final.
这是一项有三个结果的运动，对我们来说幸运的是
It is a sport that there are three results and luckily for us
Es un deporte que hay tres resultados y por suerte a nosotros
很多时候，我们得到了最好的一切，最积极的结果。
Many times we have been given the best of everything, the most positive result.
Muchas veces se nos ha dado el mejor de todo, el resultado más positivo.
但我认为这是足球的一部分，也是生活的一部分，是恢复的一部分。
But I think it is part of what football is, what life is also, of recovering.
pero creo que forma parte de lo que es el fútbol, de lo que es la vida también, de reponerse.
我相信我已经说清楚了，他们也按理知道
I believe that I have already made this clear and they also know it logically that
Yo creo que esto ya lo dejé claro y ellos también lo saben lógicamente que
失去的越少越好，但有时我根本不会说这很好，因为它不......
The less you lose, the better, but from time to time I don't say that it's good at all, because it doesn't...
que cuanto menos perdés, mejor, pero de vez en cuando no digo que venga bien para nada, porque no...
但时不时会失落看看球队表现如何
but from time to time lose to see how the team is doing
pero de vez en cuando perder para ver cómo se encuentra el equipo
很高兴看到他在逆境中如何处理这种情况。
It's good to see how he deals with the situation in the face of adversity.
Está bueno y ver cómo afronta la situación ante la adversidad.
这就是你得出好的结论的地方。
That's where you draw good conclusions.
De ahí es donde saca uno buenas conclusiones.
卡洛斯·尼克塔尔教授，下午好。
Professor Carlos Niquetal, good afternoon.
Profesor Carlos Niquetal, buenas tardes.
Walter Arrella，来自秘鲁的 Linkesport。
Walter Arrella, Linkesport from Peru.
Walter Arrella, Linkesport de Perú.
明天秘鲁队在等哪支球队？
What Peruvian team is waiting for tomorrow?
¿Qué selección peruana espera mañana?
你觉得他会打得怎么样？
How do you think he's going to play?
¿Cómo cree que va a jugar?
显然，后面一定是五人队。
Apparently it must be a line of five behind.
Aparentemente debe ser línea de cinco atrás.
防御力确实很强。
Quite defensive for sure.
bastante defensivo seguramente.
寻找平局，并且在没有进一步危险的情况下，秘鲁渴望积分
looking for a tie and, without further danger, a Peru that is desperate for points
buscando el empate y, sin más peligroso, un Perú que viene urgido de puntos
或者秘鲁在积分上不那么紧迫。
or a Peru not so urgent in points.
o un Perú no tan urgido en puntos.
您对秘鲁明天有何期待？
What do you expect tomorrow from Peru?
¿Qué espera mañana de Perú?
嗯，我认为在福萨蒂的带领下，他总是打5号线、5-3-2、5号线，嗯……
Well, I think that with Fosati he has always played a line of 5, 5-3-2, 5, well...
Bueno, yo creo que con Fosati siempre ha jugado línea de 5, 5-3-2, 5, bueno...
但我不认为对于一支防守球队来说是这样。
But I don't think so on a defensive team.
Pero no lo creo en un equipo defensivo.
不一定是因为国际米兰采用五人防守，但我可以告诉你，国际米兰是五人防守的球队。
Not necessarily because they play with a line of five on defense, Inter Milan plays with five and the most offensive team I would tell you.
No necesariamente por jugar con línea de cinco sobre defensivo, el Inter de Milán juega con cinco y el equipo más ofensivo te diría.
欧洲足球。
of European football.
del fútbol europeo.
我不认为这是一支防守球队，它有球员......
I don't think it's a defensive team, it has players...
No creo que sea un equipo defensivo, tiene jugadores...
您今天发现的有趣且典型的南美分类
interesting and typical of the South American classification that you find today
interesantes y propios de la clasificación sudamericana que hoy te encontrás
那里有两到三个负面结果
down there for two or three negative results
ahí abajo por dos o tres resultados negativos
也许他们取得了一些好的成绩，并发现自己处于我认为他们有机会获得的不同位置。
Maybe they get a couple of good results and find themselves in different positions that I think they have had the opportunity to get.
A lo mejor sacan un par de resultados buenos y se encuentran en diferentes posiciones que creo que han tenido oportunidad de sacar.
点多了你就得小心
more points then you have to be careful and
más puntos entonces hay que tener cuidado y
并专心认真地玩我们的游戏并努力获胜。
and be attentive and play our game seriously and try to win.
y estar atento y hacer nuestro partido serio e intentar ganar.
教授，你怎么在这里？
Professor, how are you here?
Profesor, ¿cómo está por acá?
美国电视台的让·保罗图片。
Jean Paul Pictures of América Television.
Jean Paul Cuadros de América Televisión.
继续上一个问题，
To continue a bit with the line of the previous question,
Para seguir un poco con la línea de la pregunta anterior,
在秘鲁，我们谈论这场比赛几乎非常普遍。
And in Peru we talk about this match almost, almost common.
Y es que en Perú se habla de este partido casi, casi común.
秘鲁有可能遭受致命一击，如果他们明天输球，我们甚至可以从数字上说。
the possibility of Peru being given the coup de grace and we would even say numerically if they end up losing tomorrow.
la posibilidad de que se le dé el tir de gracia a Perú y diríamos hasta numéricamente si termina perdiendo mañana.
你认为秘鲁会变得脆弱吗？
Do you think you are going to find a vulnerable Peru?
¿Creen que van a encontrar un Perú vulnerable?
相反，这可能会让需要出去寻找糖果盒中的点变得更加危险。
On the contrary, this perhaps makes it more dangerous in the need to go out and look for points in the candy box.
Al contrario, esto lo hace quizá más peligroso en la necesidad de salir a buscar puntos en la bombonera.
如果是这样的话，你会发现这个秘鲁的福萨蒂有什么优势。
And if that were the case, what strengths do you find in this Peru of Fosati.
Y si fuera el caso, qué fortalezas le encuentra a este Perú de Fosati.
谢谢。
Gracias.
好吧，我或多或少重复一下我告诉你的搭档的答案。
Well, I repeat more or less the answer I told your partner.
Bueno, repito más o menos la respuesta que le dije a tu compañero.
这是一支思路清晰、比赛方式相当清晰、球员经验丰富的球队。
It is a team that has things clear, plays in a fairly clear way, has experienced players.
Es un equipo que tiene las cosas claras, juega de una manera bastante clara, tiene jugadores experimentados.
在防守方面，他站稳脚跟，他必须在边路快速进攻。
In defense he has good footing, he has to play on the sides quickly.
En defensa tiene buen pie, tiene que jugar por los costados rápido.
我认为，从我们所看到的情况来看，他们可能还有更多的道理。
and I think that, from what we have seen, they could have some more point.
y creo que, por lo que hemos visto, podrían tener algún punto más.
所以你必须小心，你必须尽可能尊重
So you have to be careful, you have to respect as much as possible
Entonces hay que tener cuidado, hay que respetar al máximo
你永远不知道你会发现什么，因为分类具有误导性
and you never know what you will find because the classification is misleading
y uno nunca sabe lo que se va a encontrar por la clasificación engaña
你不必相信自己，所以他们是一支优秀的团队，我说了一切。
and you don't have to trust yourself, so they are a good team and with that I say everything.
y no hay que confiarse, así que es un buen equipo y con eso digo todo.
教授，下午好。
Professor, very good afternoon.
Profesor, muy buenas tardes.
史蒂夫·罗梅罗通过体育电视为整个秘鲁直播。
Steve Romero live for all of Peru through Sports TV.
Steve Romero en vivo para todo el Perú a través de la TV Deportes.
在阿根廷，路易斯·阿德温库拉 (Luis Advincula) 突然广为人知。
Here in Argentina suddenly a lot is known about Luis Advincula.
Aquí en Argentina de repente se conoce mucho de Luis Advincula.
在博卡踢球的桑布拉诺（Zambrano）最近也经过那里，或者保罗·格雷罗（Paolo Guerrero）在他的巅峰时期仍然是一位历史性球员
who plays in Boca, Zambrano who has also recently passed there or Paolo Guerrero who in his good moment is still a historic player
que juega en Boca, Zambrano que también ha pasado hace poco por ahí o Paolo Guerrero que en su momento bueno sigue siendo un jugador histórico
我们团队的成员，但从他们的角度来看，有一些球员
of our team but from their perspective there are some players
de nuestra selección pero desde su perspectiva hay algún jugador
秘鲁人对明天突然产生了期待。
Peruvian that tomorrow suddenly generates expectations.
peruano que mañana de repente pues genere expectativas.
在卫生部门。
in the health sector.
en el sector de salud.
对我来说，这是一支优秀的团队，我不再谈论个性，因为除此之外，我相信
For me it is a good team and I am no longer talking about individualities because apart from that I believe that
Para mí es un buen equipo y ya no hablo de individualidades porque aparte creo que
福萨蒂强化了“团队”这个词，他拥有优秀的球员。
Fosati has reinforced the word team, he has good players.
Fosati ha reforzado la palabra equipo, tiene buenos jugadores.
他有波罗，他有索奈，他有演奏出色的佩尼亚。
He has Polo, he has Sonet, he has Peña who plays well.
Tiene a Polo, tiene a Sonet, tiene a Peña que juega bien.
他有像巴勃罗格雷罗这样的顶级前锋，关于他，拉帕杜拉，没什么可说的，人们......
He has top level forwards like Pablo Guerrero, there is little to say about him, La Padula, people who...
tiene delanteros de nivel como Pablo Guerrero, que hay poco que decir de él, La Padula, gente que...
谢谢！
¡Gracias!
谁有丰富的经验并且谁参加过很多这样的比赛
who has a lot of experience and who has had many of these matches
que tiene mucha experiencia y que ha tenido muchos de estos partidos
请记住，这是一次历史性的选择，一次可能会给我们带来麻烦的选择，从那时起，这将是我们的离开
Keep in mind that it is a historic selection and it is a selection that can put us in trouble and from then on it will be our departure
en cuenta que es una selección histórica y es una selección que nos puede poner en problemas y nosotros a partir de ahí la será nuestra partida
你好，莱昂纳多·斯卡罗尼、卢卡斯·加蒂，公民。
Hello, Leonardo Scaloni, Lucas Gatti, citizen.
Hola, Leonardo Scaloni, Lucas Gatti, ciudadano.
我给你走两条捷径。
I'll make you two short cuts.
Te hago dos cortitas.
好吧，自从在马拉卡纳发表那句“你缺乏活力”的声明以来，已经过去一年了。
Well, a year has passed since that statement at the Maracaná, that you lacked energy.
Bueno, pasó un año de aquella declaración en el Maracaná, de que te faltaban energías.
今年你精神焕发了吗？你有何评价？
Did you renew your energy this year and what assessment do you make?
¿renovaste energías en este año y qué balance hacés?
至于明天的比赛呢,嗯,有九名球员是黄牌极限的。
And as for tomorrow's game, well, there are nine players who are at the limit of yellow cards.
Y en cuanto al partido de mañana, bueno, son nueve los jugadores que están al límite de amarillas.
我还记得你当时说你不想阻止玩家，你会和他们谈谈吗？
I also remember that you said at the time that you don't want to stop players, would you talk to them?
Recuerdo también que dijiste en su momento que no querés parar jugadores, ¿hablarías con ellos?
因为他们将在三月份与巴西和乌拉圭进行双重比赛，以免输掉比赛。
As they go for the double date in March against Brazil and Uruguay so as not to lose them.
de cara que se acuden para la doble fecha de marzo frente a Brasil y a Uruguay para no perderlos.
谢谢。
Gracias.
不，第一个答案来自第二个，即你的问题。
No, the first answer is from the second, your question.
No, la primera respuesta es de la segunda, pregunta tuya.
我永远不会告诉他们要照顾自己或不要照顾自己，这是重要的游戏。
I would never tell them to take care of themselves or not to take care of themselves, this is the important game.
No les diría nunca ni que se cuiden ni que no se cuiden, el partido importante es este.
我们必须继续推进这场比赛。
and we have to move forward with this game.
y hay que sacar adelante este partido.
无论发生什么，如果之后有任何损失，都会被看到
whatever happens and if there is any loss afterwards it will be seen
pase lo que pase y si después hay alguna baja ya se verá
今年也是如此，我说……
And well this year was too, I said...
Y bueno este año fue también, lo decía...
总是，正如内斯托所说，内斯托是一年
always, as Néstor said, Néstor was a year
siempre, como Néstor lo decía, Néstor fue un año
很重，美洲杯是友谊赛，那是一场预选赛。
heavy, the Copa América was friendly, that is a qualifying match.
pesado, la Copa América era amistoso, eso es partido eliminatoria.
幸运的是，我们成功了，我们来到了这里。
and luckily we pulled it off and we are here.
y por suerte lo sacamos adelante y estamos acá.
这是显而易见的，但正如我们所说，许多比赛都是非典型的年份。
That is evident, but they are atypical years, as we said, many games.
Eso es evidente, pero son años atípicos, bien lo decíamos, muchos partidos.
来到这里需要大量的精力。
and it requires a lot of energy to be here.
y requiere mucha energía estar acá.
过去，也许你在国家队呆了一段时间，然后三个月没有见到球员。
In the past, maybe you were in the national team for a little while and then you didn't see the players for three months.
Antiguamente a lo mejor en la selección estabas un tiempito y después estabas tres meses sin ver los jugadores.
现在会发生什么？
What's going to happen now?
¿Qué va a pasar ahora?
还有更多，但今年，嗯，最重要的是令人兴奋，对吧？
and there you are a little more, but this year was, well, it was and above all exciting, right?
y ahí estás un poco más, pero este año fue, bueno, fue y sobre todo emocionante, ¿no?
最后一个问题。
Last question.
Última pregunta.
我要祝贺您自 2018 年以来担任阿根廷国家队教练的第七个年头。
I want to congratulate you for closing your seventh year since 2018 as coach of the Argentine national team.
Quiero felicitarlo por cerrar su séptimo año desde el 2018 como técnico de la selección argentina.
所以？
So?
¿Así?
我是一名数学家。
I am a mathematician.
Soy matemático.
自 2022 年 12 月 18 日起。
from December 18, 2022.
desde el 18 de diciembre del 2022.
进入 2096 年，您认为迄今为止最好的改变是什么？
What do you think was the best change so far and heading into 2096?
¿Cuál cree que fue el mejor cambio hasta ahora y rumbo al 2096?
您希望这支阿根廷队在哪些方面进行改进？
What would you like to improve about this Argentine team?
qué le gustaría mejorar de este equipo argentino.
太感谢了。
Thank you so much.
Muchas gracias.
有什么变化？
What was the change?
¿Cuál fue el cambio?
感觉好像发生了变化。
It feels like there has been a change.
Se siente que hubo un cambio.
在从卡塔尔决赛到现在的过渡过程中，您希望在 2026 年之前做出哪些改进。
in this transition from the Qatar final to now and what would you like to improve towards 2026.
en esta transición desde la final de Qatar hasta ahora y qué le gustaría mejorar rumbo el 2026.
好吧，让我们看看...
Well, let's see...
Bueno, a ver...
从卡塔尔来看，这里并没有太多变化。
From Qatar there have not been many changes here.
de Qatar acá no ha habido muchos cambios.
我不知道我是否会说逻辑这个词，但是......
I don't know if I would say the word logical or not, but...
No sé si diría la palabra lógico o no, pero...
我认为我们非常信任他们，信任那些带领我们赢得冠军的人，有基础，有年轻人。
I think we trust a lot in them, in those who led us to win the championship, with a base, with young people.
Creo que confiamos mucho en ellos, en esos que nos llevaron a ganar el campeonato, con una base, con gente joven.
我们带来了小男孩，但不幸的是
We have brought young boys but unfortunately
hemos traído chicos jóvenes pero lamentablemente
因为我们有美洲杯，或者因为我们马上就要参加比赛，所以我们还没有机会尝试其他任何事情，这是我们的......
Because we have the Copa América or because we compete right away, we haven't had the chance to try anything else yet, which is ours...
por tener la Copa América o por competir enseguida, no hemos tenido posibilidad de probar todavía alguno más, que es nuestra...
这是我们的计划，并且继续在我们的计划中继续见到球员，因为另一方面我们将需要他们。
It was in our plan and it continues to be in our plan to continue seeing players because on the other hand we are going to need them.
Estaba en nuestro plan y sigue estando en nuestro plan de seguir viendo jugadores porque por otra parte los vamos a necesitar.
但我认为世界杯以来这里并没有那么多变化，我想最终
but I think there haven't been so many changes from the World Cup here, I think in the end
pero creo que no ha habido tantos cambios del Mundial acá, creo que al final
一个人脑子里能想到的一切，有时却无法实现。
Everything that one can have in his head sometimes he cannot carry out.
Todo lo que uno puede tener en su cabeza a veces no lo puede llevar a cabo.